<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <TipSetDef>
    <defName>CombatExtendedCoreTips</defName>
    <tips>
      <!-- Interface-->
		<li>Use loadouts to determine what your colonists should carry in their inventory. Use the equipment tab to access items.</li>
		
      <!-- Combat -->
		<li>The most important part of a mortar squad is an experienced spotter with a good pair of binoculars.</li>
		<li>If your colonist can't hit the broad side of a barn, perhaps they are vision-impaired, less conscious or they weren't told to aim their shots.</li>
		<li>Fewer things are deadlier than a well-prepared kill zone.</li>		
		<li>Simple, durable projectiles such as steel or plasteel arrows can survive the force of impact to be re-used by you or your enemies.</li>
		<li>Select a colonist carrying medicine and right click a downed comrade (or foe) to ordered them to "stabilize" the target, temporarily stanching their bleeding.</li>
		<li>Stabilizing someone temporarily staunches their bleeding, but it does not treat the wound. How long it lasts depends on the medic's skill.</li>
		<li>Bloodloss is often as fatal as the enemy fire. Tend to the wounded quickly to save allies and capture foes.</li>
		<li>Some weapons, such as one-handed pistols and melee weapons, can be used in conjuction with a shield, although doing so will expose the users arms.</li>
		<li>Centipedes are extremely well armored mechanoids, intended to shrug off small arms fire and break defensive lines. Defeating them requires special weapons and tactics.</li>
		<li>Stockpiling ammunition close to your emplacements keeps it handy during combat. Just watch out for cook-off!</li>
		<li>Targets are more difficult to spot in darkness, but shooters aren't penalized for being in the dark. Light 'em up!</li>
	<!--<li>If either shooter or target is unroofed in bad weather, accuracy diminishes.</li>-->
	<!--<li>Any dense smoke in the way of a shooter and their target has detrimental effects on accuracy.</li>-->
	<!--<li>Targets in dense smoke may experience negative health effects without a gas mask. At least they become more difficult to hit.</li>-->
		<li>Good sights can help negate inaccuracy due to bad weather, darkness, or dense smoke.</li>
		<li>Shooters imperfectly lead their targets until they commit to a shot. Slower projectiles can be dodged.</li>
		<li>Some weapons, such as shotguns, are often reloaded one round at a time, allowing them to be fired mid-reload.</li>
		<li>Even when a projectile doesn't penetrate a character's armor, they may still be injured by the force of the impact.</li>
		<li>Even when behind cover, a shooter's head will still be exposed as they scan for targets.</li>
		<li>The longer a wound remains untreated, the higher the risk of infection. Lying in the dirt doesn't help things either.</li>
		<li>Combat Extended's changes to weapon range and lethality make many tactics from vanilla Rimworld ill-advised.</li>
  	<li>Never underestimate the effects of flanking and enfilades.</li>
    
	  <!-- Melee -->	
		<li>Your chance to hit, parry, dodge or land a critical hit in melee is a comparison between your and the enemy skill. The higher the difference in skill levels, the bigger the disparity.</li>
		<li>Your choice of weapon significantly affects your change to hit, parry, dodge or land a critical hit.</li>
		<li>Melee weapons can score critical hits. Blunt weapons will inflict a short stun, sharp weapons double their armor penetration, and animals knock down their target.</li>
		<li>Heavy, blunt melee weapons may defeat thick armor when edged weapons fail.</li>
		<li>Scoring a critical hit on a parry gives you a free riposte attack.</li>
		
	  <!-- Suppression -->	
		<li>Characters under enemy fire will become suppressed, diminishing their effectiveness in combat. Under especially heavy fire, they will seek cover and hunker down to avoid being killed.</li>
		<li>Projectiles will generate suppression enemies along their entire trajectory.</li>		
		<li>Suppressed characters are indicated with a yellow downwards arrow. Suppression incurs mood debuffs, prevents aiming shots, and lowers accuracy.</li>
		<li>Hunkering characters emit an orange downwards arrow and dive for the nearest cover, where they build courage to return to the fight.</li>
		<li>Armor and specialized items like war masks make characters less suceptible to supression.</li>

		
	  <!-- Items & Weapons -->
		<li>Armor-piercing ammo offers superior armor penetration, but less damage than FMJ. The reverse is true for Hollow-Points.</li>	  
		<li>Shotguns can fire a variety of special ammunition types, such as EMP and non-lethal beanbags.</li>
		<li>Guns vary in calibre, accepted ammo types, long-range accuracy, magazine size.. Find out more by reading their information tab!</li>
		<li>Weapons excel in their respective roles: shotguns and SMG's are lethal at close range, sniper rifles attack from afar, machine guns can sustain suppression, rifles strike a balance.</li>
		<li>Shotguns can use a variety of special ammunition types such as EMP and non-lethal beanbags.</li>
		<li>EMP will inflict electrical burns on anyone in the blast radius. Mechanoids take doubled damage.</li>
		<li>You can rely on enemies to drop ammunition, or you can craft it yourself at a machining table or a loading bench.</li>
		
	  <!-- Environment -->
		<li>Precipitation, wind direction and speed all have a significant effect on fire spread. Beware of being downwind from a bush fire.</li>
		<li>Indoor fires will create clouds of lethal smoke. Use gas masks to protect yourself.</li>
		
	  <!-- Mechanoids -->
		<li>Mechanoids are extremely well armored mechanoids intended to shrug off small arms fire and break defensive lines. Defeating them requires special weapons and tactics.</li>
		<li>Large mechanoids' 20 mmRHA armour outperforms most armoured personnel carriers. Stock up on high penetration ammunition if you plan to take one out.</li>
		<li>Don't try to shiv the giant murderbot.</li>
		<li>Centipedes carry heavy assault weapons that can easily punch through heavy armor and cover. Their long range and accuracy make them deadly.</li>
		
	  <!-- Insect hives -->
		<li>Smoke from fires will block insectoid pheromones and pacify them, allowing easy access to their hives.</li>
  
	</tips>
  </TipSetDef>
</Defs>