<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <TipSetDef>
    <defName>CombatExtendedCoreTips</defName>
    <tips>
      <!-- Interface-->
	<!--<li>You can set loadouts for pawns.</li>-->
		
      <!-- Combat -->
		<li>The most destructive equipment in a mortar squad is a good pair of binoculars on an experienced spotter.</li>
		<li>If your colonist can't hit the broad side of a barn, perhaps they are vision-impaired, less conscious or they weren't told to aim their shots.</li>
		<li>Simple, strong projectiles such as plasteel arrows survive the force of impact and can be re-used by you or your enemies.</li>
		<li>Keep combat medics at the ready or use less-lethal beanbag ammunition if you plan to keep survivors after a firefight.</li>
		<li>Bleed-out is common and lethal. Any colonist with medicine in their inventory can stabilize a bleeding creature.</li>
		<li>Shields combine well with one-handed pistols and -melee weapons, although using these weapons puts your arms in harm's way.</li>
		<li>Large mechanoids' 20 mmRHA armour outperforms most armoured personnel carriers. Stock up on high penetration ammunition if you plan to take one out.</li>
		<li>Ammunition stockpiles near your artillery allow for more rapid reloading. Just watch out for cook-off!</li>
		<li>Sustained gun fire penalizes accuracy, so it is especially useful on clumped up, nearby targets.</li>
		<li>Targets are more difficult to spot in darkness, but shooters aren't penalized for being in darkness. Light 'em up!</li>
		<li>Suppressed targets emit a yellow downwards arrow. Suppression incurs mood debuffs, prevents aiming shots and lowers accuracy.</li>
		<li>Hunkering targets emit an orange downwards arrow and dive for the nearest cover, where they build courage to return to the fight.</li>
	<!--<li>If either shooter or target is unroofed in bad weather, accuracy diminishes.</li>-->
	<!--<li>Any dense smoke in the way of a shooter and their target has detrimental effects on accuracy.</li>-->
	<!--<li>Targets in dense smoke may experience negative health effects without a gas mask. At least they become more difficult to hit.</li>-->
		<li>Good sights can negate inaccuracy due to bad weather, targets in darkness or targets in dense smoke.</li>
		<li>Shooters imperfectly lead their targets until they commit to a shot. Slower projectiles can be dodged.</li>
		<li>Gunmen are defenseless while they reload their gun. However, shotguns are often reloaded one-by-one, allowing them to be fired mid-reload.</li>
		<li>Moving pawns are much larger targets than still, crouching pawns. A crouched gunner reveals just enough to fire a shot.</li>
		
	  <!-- Items -->
		<li>Guns vary in calibre, accepted ammo types, long-range accuracy, magazine size.. Find out more by reading their information tab!</li>
		<li>Thick armour instills courage against small arms fire, but its bulkiness reduces work speed.</li>
		<li>You can rely on enemies to drop ammunition, or you can craft it yourself at a machining table or a loading bench.</li>
		<li>Boomalope herds and blazebulb fields are just about volatile enough for explosive ordnance.</li>
		
	</tips>
  </TipSetDef>
</Defs>