<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <!--=============== Concepts taught in modal dialogs ===========-->

  <ConceptDef>
    <defName>CE_ArmorSystem</defName>
    <label>CE: New armor system</label>
    <priority>-1000</priority>
    <helpText>Combat Extended replaces the vanilla armor system with a penetration-based model. Blunt and sharp type weapons have armor penetration values which determine how much their damage is reduced by armor.\n\nA weapon hitting armor equal to its penetration will do 50% damage. If armor is twice the penetration it will do no damage, if it is half the penetration the full damage goes through.\n\nSharp damage additionally needs to check against deflection. If penetration is equal to armor there is a 50% chance for deflection. Deflected attacks are converted into blunt damage, preventing bleeding and internal organ damage.\n\nEnvironmental damage such as fire/electricity has no penetration and is simply reduced by the % of armor against that type.</helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <!--<ConceptDef>
    <defName>CE_LowPenetrationAmmo</defName>
    <label>CE: Low armor penetration</label>
    <priority>-1000</priority>
    <helpText>Warning: The ammo you picked up has a very low armor penetration value. It will have trouble penetrating even basic synthread clothing. If you plan on taking on spacers you should acquire better ammo quickly.</helpText>
  </ConceptDef>-->

  <ConceptDef>
    <defName>CE_SuppressionReaction</defName>
    <label>CE: Suppression</label>
    <priority>-1000</priority>
    <helpText>All humans have a suppression meter, based on their mental break threshold and current mood. Any time gunfire passes by them, it will add to the meter based on projectile power and (lack of) worn armor. \n\nWhen someone's suppression threshold is reached they will panic, run for the nearest cover and become incapable of using aimed shot mode, making it a good tool to break up melee charges or reduce sniper accuracy. It will also impart a mood penalty, making them easier to suppress in the future.\n\nYou can recognize suppressed pawns by the yellow downwards arrow they're emitting.</helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

  <ConceptDef>
    <defName>CE_Hunkering</defName>
    <label>CE: Hunkering</label>
    <priority>-1000</priority>
    <helpText>If someone's suppression meter maxes out they will hunker in panic. This causes them to run for the nearest cover and lie down, unable to shoot back or take any action until their suppression ticks down, essentially removing them from the fight.\n\nHunkering pawns are marked by an orange downwards arrow.</helpText>
  </ConceptDef>
  
  <ConceptDef>
    <defName>CE_WornBulk</defName>
    <label>CE: Bulky clothing</label>
    <priority>-1000</priority>
    <helpText>Certain clothing items are very bulky and will hinder your colonists in their daily tasks, lowering work speed when worn. These items include things like armor and regular clothing made from certain materials such as hyperweave.\n\nYou can check the info-menu of a particular apparel to see its 'worn bulk' stat to see how much bulk it adds when equipped on a colonist.</helpText>
  </ConceptDef>

</Defs>